Guide to the Eugene V. Dennett Papers
Special Collections, University of Washington Libraries
Eugene V. Dennett papers
1928-1988
University of Washington Libraries Special Collections Box 352900 Seattle, WA 98195-2900
3917
3917-002
Dennett, Eugene V.,$d1908-
9 cubic feet
Communist Party member 1931-47, and organizer
Eugene Dennett was born in 1908 in Revere, Massachusetts to a working-class family. His parents named him for the Socialist leader, Eugene V. Debs. Dennett attended Oregon Normal School and taught school until 1931. In the 1930s he joined the Communist Party under the name Victor Haines and in 1931 became Agitation and Propaganda Director for the Communist Party, Northwestern District Buro in Seattle. As a result of conflict with the District Organizer, Dennett was sent to Bellingham in 1932 as Party section organizer. He eventually drifted away from active participation in the Communist Party because of his political disagreements with the district leadership. In 1934 he joined the Civilian Conservation Corps and edited CCC camp newspapers at Yale, Washington and Metaline Falls, Washington. He was discharged from this job in 1935 because of his radical pro-labor leanings.
Dennett moved to Seattle, found a job on a ferry boat, joined the Ferryboatmen's Union (later renamed the Inlandboatmen's Union), and took part in strikes in 1935 and 1936. He was a ship delegate and chaired a "Committee of Nine" which was assigned the task of interpreting and applying the decision of the Governor's review and arbitration commission following settlement of the strike in 1936. When the IBU joined the Maritime Federation of the Pacific Coast, Dennett was elected one of the IBU's delegates to the Federation's Puget Sound District Council and to the Federation's third convention in 1937. He also served as IBU delegate to the Seattle Central Labor Council from 1936 to 1937.
After rejoining the Communist Party in 1936, Dennett was active in the Washington Commonwealth Federation and served as WCF Vice President from 1938 to 1940. In 1937 he managed Hugh DeLacy's successful campaign for Seattle City Council. In 1938 he was elected the first Executive Secretary of the new Washington State Industrial Union Council (CIO), serving two years before he and other left-wing executive board members were removed at John L. Lewis' orders.
Dennett next went to work at Bethlehem Steel, Seattle, and joined the Steel Workers Organizing Committee. Meanwhile, Dennett and his wife, Harriette, led a large Communist Party unit in a working class Seattle neighborhood during the early years of World War II. In 1943 Dennett was drafted into the Army. After the war, he returned to Bethlehem Steel. His disagreements with the Communist Party led to his expulsion in 1947 on charges of being an FBI agent. He continued his activity in Steelworkers Local 1208, holding the office of Recording Secretary and serving on the local's Grievance Committee. After conflicts with the union hierarchy and Bethlehem management he was expelled from the union in 1954. In 1955 he was subpoenaed by the House Un-American Activities Committee. Following his initial resistance, Dennett testified before the Committee about his past associations with the Party. He continued working at the mill until 1966 when a confrontation with management and health problems induced him to retire.
Dennett worked several years as a longshoremen's cargo checker on the Seattle docks until his retirement in 1972. In 1979 he visited China as a member of a U.S. Booksellers Delegation to the PRC. He died in 1989.
For further biographical information, see Eugene Dennett's autobiography, Agitprop, The Life Of An American Working-Class Radical, 1990.
The Dennett papers were processed in preliminary fashion soon after they were received. Processing of the papers was completed in 1991. They were subgrouped according to Dennett's activities, with a large group of material unrelated to any of the subgroups designated as Personal Papers subgroup. A speech and a letter which had been received from Dennett in 1988 and accessioned as #3917, were integrated into this accession during processing in 1991.
Near the end of processing, a substantial number of documents that did not fit well together or in any of the subject files in the Personal Papers subgroup were separated into three groups designated "Miscellany." The following is a brief description of the types of material in each group. Political Issues and Campaigns--includes much Democratic Party information, pamphlets, memorabilia, brochures, newsletters, some personal notes.
Health--much of this is correspondence with the Veterans Administration, American Red Cross, and several doctors and hospitals regarding Dennett's various ailments. Also included are brochures, questionnaires, test results, clippings.
Labor--these are individual items collected by Dennett through his associations in the labor movement, but not extensive enough to warrant a subgroup or subject file. They include constitutions, ephemera, contracts, agreements, acts, newsletters, resolutions. The record series, "Miscellany," was used, to a lesser degree, in other subgroups as well, for unsorted material of any kind. All of Dennett's papers relating to his service in the CCC are in the subgroup, u.s. civilian Conservation Corps. Company 1745. All of his papers relating to his activities on behalf of the Communist Party are in the subgroup, Communist Party, U.S.A. District 12. Transcripts and material relating to Dennett's later testimony about the Party are in the Personal Papers subgroup.
Correspondence, reports, minutes, writings, ephemera, clippings, photographs, and related papers.
Access restricted: For terms of access, contact Special Collections for details.
Donated by Eugene Dennett; 1988; estate of Eugene Dennett, deposit; 6/27/89, 9/89, 6/27/1989.
Dennett, Eugene V.,$d1908- $vArchives; DeLacy, Hugh,$d1910-1986; Costigan, Barbara; Haines, Victor; Gilland, Rolland L.; Dennett, Harriette; Labor Archives of Washington (University of Washington); United States.$bCongress.$bHouse.$bCommittee on Un-American Activities; Maritime Federation of the Pacific Coast; Bethlehem Steel Company; Washington Industrial Union Council; Communist Party of the United States of America.$bDistrict 12; United Steelworkers of America.$bLocal 1208 (Seattle, Wash.); Industrial Union Council (Seattle, Wash.); Inland Boatmen's Union of the Pacific.$bPuget Sound Division; Civilian Conservation Corps (U.S.).$bCompany 1745 (Wash.); Washington Commonwealth Federation; Central Labor Council of Seattle and Vicinity; Personal Papers/Corporate Records; Labor History; Labor Unions; Washington (State); Seattle
- EUGENE V. DENNETT PAPERS, 1898-1988; RECORD GROUP I (Box-folder 1/1-19/9)
  - Communist Party, U.S.A., District 12, 1893-1988; Record Subgroup A (Box-folder 1/1-2/10)
    - CONSTITUTION, 1945-1947; SERIES I (Box-folder 1/1)
      - Constitutions, Communist Party, U.S.A., 1945-1947 (Box-folder 1/1)
    - CORRESPONDENCE, 1932-1948; SERIES II (Box-folder 1/2-1/5)
      - Incoming Letters, 1933-1948 (Box-folder 1/2)
      - Outgoing Letters, 1932-1934 (Box-folder 1/3)
      - Inter-organizational Correspondence, 1932-1947 (Box-folder 1/4)
      - General Correspondence, 1932-1933 (Box-folder 1/5)
    - MEMORANDA AND WRITINGS, 1893, 1939; SERIES III (Box-folder 1/6-1/9)
      - Memoranda, 1939 (Box-folder 1/6)
      - Writings: "The Communist Party" (Chapter 7 of Why Communism, with study questions) by Moissaiye J. Olgin and "Democratic Centralism", Undated (Box-folder 1/7)
      - Writings: "Elements of Political Education", "Fundamental Problems of Marxism", and "On Tactics of Communists in a United Front", Undated (Box-folder 1/8)
      - Writings: "Socialism: Scientific and Utopian" by F. Engels and "Striking Against 'Forced Labor'", 1893 (Box-folder 1/9)
    - MISCELLANEOUS, 1934; SERIES IV (Box-folder 1/10, 2/10)
      - Miscellanous, 1934 (Box-folder 1/10)
      - Miscellanous, Undated (Box-folder 2/10)
    - REPORTS AND RESOLUTIONS, 1932-1937; SERIES V (Box-folder 1/11-1/13)
      - Report on Anacortes Trial at Mt. Vernon, Plan of Action for Northwest District, Political reports to the Units, Report on May Day (Bellingham), 1932-1933 (Box-folder 1/11)
      - District 12 Draft Resolutions, 1932-1934 (Box-folder 1/12)
      - Resolution of Tasks of the Communist Party, U.S.A. and Resolution on Inner Party Situation and Explusion of Members, Undated (Box-folder 1/13)
    - STATEMENTS, 1932-1947; SERIES VI (Box-folder 1/14)
      - Statements, 1932-1947 (Box-folder 1/14)
    - CAMPAIGN MATERIALS, 1928-1932; SERIES VII (Box-folder 1/15)
      - Campaign materials, 1928-1932 (Box-folder 1/15)
    - PRINTED MATERIALS, 1931-1988; SERIES VIII (Box-folder 1/16-1/22)
      - Bulletins, Undated (Box-folder 1/16)
      - Pamphlets, 1933-1947 (Box-folder 1/17)
      - Newsletters, 1931 (Box-folder 1/18)
      - Newspapers: People's Daily World and Voice of Action, 1933,-1986 (Box-folder 1/19)
      - Newspapers: Miscellaneous, 1931-1933 (Box-folder 1/20)
      - Clippings, 1976-1988 (Box-folder 1/21)
      - Notes: "On Victory and After" and miscellaneous, Undated (Box-folder 1/22)
    - SUBJECT SERIES, 1930-1948; SERIES IX (Box-folder 1/23-2/7)
      - Agitprop (Part 1 of 2), 1930-1931 (Box-folder 1/23)
      - Agitprop (Part 2 of 2), 1930-1931 (Box-folder 1/24)
      - Communist Party of Japan, Undated (Box-folder 1/25)
      - Dennet's Expulsion from Communist Party, U.S.A, 1947-1948 (Box-folder 1/26)
      - Pioneer Summer School (Seattle), Undated (Box-folder 1/27)
      - Worker's School (Part 1 of 3), Undated (Box-folder 1/28)
      - Worker's School (Part 2 of 3), Undated (Box-folder 1/29)
      - Worker's School (Part 3 of 3), Undated (Box-folder 1/30)
      - Friends of the Soviet Union, Undated (Box-folder 2/1)
      - International Labor Defense, Undated (Box-folder 2/2)
      - Trade Union Unity League, Undated (Box-folder 2/3)
      - Unemployed Council (incl. National Committee Unemployed Council), 1932-1933 (Box-folder 2/4)
      - People's Councils, Bellingham (Part 1 of 2), 1932 (Box-folder 2/5)
      - People's Councils, Bellingham (Part 2 of 2), 1932 (Box-folder 2/6)
      - Unemployed Citizens League, Central Federation (and others), 1933-1934 (Box-folder 2/7)
    - EPHEMERA, Undated; SERIES X (Box-folder 2/8-2/9)
      - Communist Party, Undated (Box-folder 2/8)
      - Miscellaneous related, Undated (Box-folder 2/9)
  - U.S. Civilian Conservation Corps. Company 1745 (later 2920), 1924-1935; Record Subgroup B (Box-folder 2/11-3/5)
    - CORRESPONDENCE, 1934-1935; SERIES I (Box-folder 2/11-2/13)
      - Incoming Letters, 1934-1935 (Box-folder 2/11)
      - Outgoing Letters, 1935 (Box-folder 2/12)
      - General Correspondence, 1934 (Box-folder 2/13)
    - REPORTS, 1931-1935; SERIES II (Box-folder 2/14-2/15)
      - Report of personnel survey, 1935 (Box-folder 2/14)
      - Miscellaneous reports, 1931-1935 (Box-folder 2/15)
    - NEWSLETTERS, 1934-1935; SERIES III (Box-folder 2/16-2/26)
      - Company 1745 ("1745th Post"; E.V. Dennett, editor), 1935 (Box-folder 2/16)
      - Company 2920 ("2920th Post"; E.V. Dennett, editor), 1935 (Box-folder 2/17)
      - Company 177 ("Camp Chapman Clarion"), 1935 (Box-folder 2/18)
      - Company 928 ("Zigzag Zephyr"), 1935 (Box-folder 2/19)
      - Company 931 ("931 News"), 1935 (Box-folder 2/20)
      - Company 932 ("The War Whoop"), 1935 (Box-folder 2/21)
      - Company 935 ("The Salt Water Herald"), 1934 (Box-folder 2/22)
      - Company 969 ("The Broomhandle"), 1935 (Box-folder 2/23)
      - Company 1624 ("The Tide), 1935 (Box-folder 2/24)
      - Company 2907 ("The Daily Blast"), 1935 (Box-folder 2/25)
      - Company 2912 ("The Emulator"), 1935 (Box-folder 2/26)
    - BULLETINS AND PUBLICATIONS, 1924-1935; SERIES IV (Box-folder 2/27-2/29)
      - Bulletins, 1934-1935 (Box-folder 2/27)
      - Publication: "Uncle Sam's Diary", 1934-1935 (Box-folder 2/28)
      - Publication: Miscellaneous, 1924-1935 (Box-folder 2/29)
    - NEWSPAPERS, 1935; SERIES V (Box-folder 2/30)
      - The Metaline Falls News, 1935 (Box-folder 2/30)
    - PHOTOGRAPHS, Undated; SERIES VI (Box-folder 3/1)
      - Photographs, Undated (Box-folder 3/1)
    - NOTES, Undated; SERIES VII (Box-folder 3/2)
      - Notes, Undated (Box-folder 3/2)
    - SUBJECT SERIES, 1934-1935; SERIES VIII (Box-folder 3/3-3/4)
      - Education, 1934-1935 (Box-folder 3/3)
      - E.V.Dennett discharge, 1935 (Box-folder 3/4)
    - MISCELLANEOUS, Undated; SERIES IX (Box-folder 3/5)
      - Miscellaneous, Undated (Box-folder 3/5)
  - Washington Commonwealth Federation, 1934-1951; Record Subgroup C (Box-folder 3/6-3/21)
    - CONSTITUTION AND BYLAWS, 1936; SERIES I (Box-folder 3/6)
      - Constitutions and Bylaws, 1936 (Box-folder 3/6)
    - CORRESPONDENCE AND MEMORANDA, 1936-1937; SERIES II (Box-folder 3/7-3/8)
      - General Correspondence, 1936 (Box-folder 3/7)
      - Memorandum, 1937 (Box-folder 3/8)
    - SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, 1940,-1951; SERIES III (Box-folder 3/9)
      - "Program of State A. F. of L. Convention Shows Influence" by E.V.Dennett (Undated), Address by E.V. Dennett from KIRO Radio (1940), Peacemakers' Manifesto to the People of Puerto Rico by E.R. Bromley, W.F.Nelson, and R.T.Templing (1951), "Principles of the Washington Commonwealth Federation" (Undated), 1940, 1951 (Box-folder 3/9)
    - INTERORGANIZATIONAL MATERIALS, 1936; SERIES IV (Box-folder 3/10-3/13)
      - Minutes: State Convention (1936), Resolutions and Platform Committee (Undated), Caucus Meeting (Undated) (Box-folder 3/10)
      - Reports from the Platform Committee, Undated (Box-folder 3/11)
      - Resolution, Undated (Box-folder 3/12)
      - Election Materials, 1936 (Box-folder 3/13)
    - CASE FILES, 1943; SERIES V (Box-folder 3/14)
      - Case File: Thompson, William, 1943 (Box-folder 3/14)
    - PAMPHLETS, 1934-1936; SERIES VI (Box-folder 3/15)
      - Pamphlets, 1934-1936 (Box-folder 3/15)
    - LISTS, Undated; SERIES VII (Box-folder 3/16)
      - Lists, Undated (Box-folder 3/16)
    - NOTES, Undated; SERIES VIII (Box-folder 3/17)
      - Note, Undated (Box-folder 3/17)
    - SUBJECT SERIES, 1937-1946; SERIES IX (Box-folder 3/18-3/20)
      - DeLacy, Hugh, 1937-1946 (Box-folder 3/18)
      - Gunther,Earl, Undated (Box-folder 3/19)
      - DeLacy-Gunther campaign for election to Seattle City Council, 1937 (Box-folder 3/20)
    - MISCELLANEOUS, 1937; SERIES X (Box-folder 3/21)
      - Miscellaneous, 1937 (Box-folder 3/21)
  - Inlandboatmen's Union of the Pacific. Puget Sound Division (Ferryboatmen's Union of the Pacific. Puget Sound Division), 1935-1986; Record Subgroup D (Box-folder 3/22-4/4)
    - CONSTITUTION AND BYLAWS, Undated; SERIES I (Box-folder 3/22)
      - Constitution and Bylaws, Undated (Box-folder 3/22)
    - CORRESPONDENCE, 1935-1938; SERIES II (Box-folder 3/23-3/26)
      - Incoming Letters, 1936-1938 (Box-folder 3/23)
      - Outgoing Letters, 1935-1937 (Box-folder 3/24)
      - Inter-organizational Correspondence, 1936-1937 (Box-folder 3/25)
      - General Correspondence, 1936-1937 (Box-folder 3/26)
    - MINUTES AND REPORTS, 1935-1937; SERIES III (Box-folder 3/27-3/29)
      - Minutes, 1937 (Box-folder 3/27)
      - Reports of Committee elected to Interpret the Martin Award ("Committee of Nine"), c.1936 (Box-folder 3/28)
      - Ship Delegate's Reports (1935), Miscellaneous Reports (1936), 1935-1936 (Box-folder 3/29)
    - RESOLUTIONS, 1936; SERIES IV (Box-folder 3/30)
      - Resolution on Arbitration Award of Governor Martin's Commission (1936), Miscellaneous (Undated) (Box-folder 3/30)
    - STATEMENTS, Undated; SERIES V (Box-folder 3/31)
      - Statement, Undated (Box-folder 3/31)
    - AGREEMENTS, 1935-1941; SERIES VI (Box-folder 3/32)
      - Agreements, 1935-1941 (Box-folder 3/32)
    - CONVENTIONS, 1936-1937; SERIES VII (Box-folder 3/33-3/34)
      - Third Annual Convention of the Maritime Federation of the Pacific Coast, 1937 (Box-folder 3/33)
      - Thirty-fifth Annual Convention of the Washington State Federation of Labor, 1936 (Box-folder 3/34)
    - ELECTION MATERIALS, 1937; SERIES VIII (Box-folder 3/35)
      - Election Materials, 1937 (Box-folder 3/35)
    - CASE FILES, 1936; SERIES IX (Box-folder 3/36)
      - Case File: Grievance Committee hearing against E.V.Dennett, 1936 (Box-folder 3/36)
    - PRINTED MATERIALS, 1935-1942; SERIES X (Box-folder 3/37-3/41)
      - Bulletins, 1937 (Box-folder 3/37)
      - Newsletters: Ferryboatmen's Union News, 1936 (Box-folder 3/38)
      - Membership books - E.V.Dennett, 1935-1937 (Box-folder 3/39)
      - Time book - E.V. Dennett, 1941-1942 (Box-folder 3/40)
      - Clippings, 1937 (Box-folder 3/41)
    - LISTS AND NOTES, 1936-1937; SERIES XI (Box-folder 3/42-3/43)
      - Lists, 1936-1937 (Box-folder 3/42)
      - Notes, Undated (Box-folder 3/43)
    - SUBJECT SERIES, 1935-1986; SERIES XII (Box-folder 3/44-4/2)
      - Masters, Mates and Pilots of America, National Organization. Local No.90 and Local No. 6, 1937 (Box-folder 3/44)
      - Ferryboatmen's Strike, 1935 (Box-folder 3/45)
      - E.V. Dennett's Discharge from the Belana, 1936 (Box-folder 3/46)
      - Maritime Federation of the Pacific Coast, 1937-1938 (Box-folder 3/47)
      - Longshoremen's and Warehousemen's Union. International, 1961-1986 (Box-folder 4/1)
      - Longshoremen's and Warehousemen's Union, International. Local No. 52 and Local No. 9, 1966-1967 (Box-folder 4/2)
    - EPHEMERA, 1936-1937; SERIES XIII (Box-folder 4/3)
      - Ephemera (Box-folder 4/3)
    - MISCELLANY, 1936-1937; SERIES XIV (Box-folder 4/4)
      - Miscellaneous (Box-folder 4/4)
  - Seattle Central Labor Council, Record Subgroup E (Box-folder 4/5-4/12)
    - CORRESPONDENCE, 1936-1937; SERIES I (Box-folder 4/5)
      - General Correspondence, 1936-1937 (Box-folder 4/5)
    - WRITINGS, 1988; SERIES II (Box-folder 4/6)
      - "Seattle Central Labor Council, 52 Years Ago" by E.V. Dennett, 1988 (Box-folder 4/6)
    - MINUTES AND REPORTS, 1935-1937; SERIES III (Box-folder 4/7-4/8)
      - Minutes, 1937 (Box-folder 4/7)
      - Reports, 1935-1936 (Box-folder 4/8)
    - RESOLUTIONS, Undated; SERIES IV (Box-folder 4/9)
      - Resolution, Undated (Box-folder 4/9)
    - SUBJECT SERIES, 1936-1937; SERIES V (Box-folder 4/10-4/11)
      - Political Welfare Committee, 1936-1937 (Box-folder 4/10)
      - Labor Day Parade, 1936 (Box-folder 4/11)
    - MISCELLANEOUS, 1935-1937; SERIES VI (Box-folder 4/12)
      - Miscellany (Box-folder 4/12)
  - Industrial Union Council, Seattle, Record Subgroup F (Box-folder 4/13-4/15)
    - CONSTITUTION, SERIES I (Box-folder 4/13)
      - Constitution (Box-folder 4/13)
    - CORRESPONDENCE, 1938; SERIES II (Box-folder 4/14)
      - General Correspondence - Molthan, James A., 1938 (Box-folder 4/14)
    - SPEECHES, 1937; SERIES III (Box-folder 4/15)
      - "The Business Recession and Unemployment" by E.V. Dennett, 1937 (Box-folder 4/15)
  - Industrial Union Council, Washington (CIO), Record Subgroup G (Box-folder 4/16-5/32)
    - CONSTITUTIONS, 1938-1950; SERIES I (Box-folder 4/16)
      - Constitutions, 1938-1950 (Box-folder 4/16)
    - CORRESPONDENCE, 1938-1941; SERIES II (Box-folder 4/17-4/22)
      - Incoming Letters, 1938-1940 (Box-folder 4/17)
      - Outgoing Letters, 1938-1941 (Box-folder 4/18)
      - Inter-organizational Correspondence, 1938-1940 (Box-folder 4/19)
      - General Correspondence - Jackson, Gardner, 1938-1940 (Box-folder 4/20)
      - General Correspondence - Miscellaneous, Part 1 of 2, 1938-1941 (Box-folder 4/21)
      - General Correspondence - Miscellaneous, Part 2 of 2, 1938-1941 (Box-folder 4/22)
    - MEMORANDA, 1938-1940; SERIES III (Box-folder 4/23-4/24)
      - Daily Memos, 1940 (Box-folder 4/23)
      - Miscellaneous, 1938-1940 (Box-folder 4/24)
    - SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, 1940; SERIES IV (Box-folder 4/25)
      - Speech before the Roslyn-Cle Elum Industrial Union Council by E.V. Dennett (1940) and "John L. Lewis and the Washington State CIO Council" by E.V. Dennett (Undated) (Box-folder 4/25)
    - MINUTES, 1938-1940; SERIES V (Box-folder 4/26-4/28)
      - Executive Board meetings, 1938-1940 (Box-folder 4/26)
      - Meetings of other Industrial Union Councils, 1940 (Box-folder 4/27)
      - Dennett's personal notes of CIO Executive Board meetings, 1939 (Box-folder 4/28)
    - REPORTS AND RESOLUTIONS, 1939-1940; SERIES VI (Box-folder 4/29-4/30)
      - Report to the Executive Board of the Washington State Industrial Union Council by E.V. Dennett (1939), Report on session of the Washington State Legislature by E.V. Dennett (1939), Miscellaneous Reports (1940, Undated), 1939-1940 (Box-folder 4/29)
      - Resolutions, 1940 (Box-folder 4/30)
    - STATEMENTS, 1942; SERIES VII (Box-folder 5/1)
      - Statements, 1942 (Box-folder 5/1)
    - CONVENTIONS, 1939-1943; SERIES VIII (Box-folder 5/2-5/13)
      - Second Annual Convention, 1939 (Box-folder 5/2)
      - Third Annual Convention: Speech - opening address by Richard Francis, 1940 (Box-folder 5/3)
      - Third Annual Convention: Minutes, 1940 (Box-folder 5/4)
      - Third Annual Convention: Reports, 1940 (Box-folder 5/5)
      - Third Annual Convention: Resolutions, 1940 (Box-folder 5/6)
      - Third Annual Convention: Statement, 1940 (Box-folder 5/7)
      - Third Annual Convention: Declaration, 1940 (Box-folder 5/8)
      - Third Annual Convention: Program, 1940 (Box-folder 5/9)
      - Third Annual Convention: Subject - Credentials Committee, 1940 (Box-folder 5/10)
      - Third Annual Convention: Miscellaneous, 1940 (Box-folder 5/11)
      - "J.C. Lewis" Convention, 1941 (Box-folder 5/12)
      - Fifth Annual Convention, 1943 (Box-folder 5/13)
    - AFFIDAVITS, 1940; SERIES IX (Box-folder 5/14)
      - Affidavits, 1940 (Box-folder 5/14)
    - FINANCIAL RECORDS, 1940; SERIES X (Box-folder 5/15)
      - Financial Records, 1940 (Box-folder 5/15)
    - FIELD TRIP RECORDS, 1940; SERIES XI (Box-folder 5/16)
      - Field Trip Records, 1940 (Box-folder 5/16)
    - NEWS RELEASES AND BULLETINS, 1936-1940; SERIES XII (Box-folder 5/17-5/18)
      - News Releases, 1939-1940 (Box-folder 5/17)
      - Bulletins, 1936 (Box-folder 5/18)
    - ADDRESS FILES, Undated; SERIES XIII (Box-folder 5/19-5/20)
      - Address file (Part 1 of 2), Undated (Box-folder 5/19)
      - Address file (Part 2 of 2), Undated (Box-folder 5/20)
    - CLIPPINGS, LISTS, and NOTES, 1938-1940; SERIES XIV (Box-folder 5/21-5/24)
      - Clippings, 1938 (Box-folder 5/21)
      - Lists: Local, Undated (Box-folder 5/22)
      - Lists: Miscellaneous, 1940 (Box-folder 5/23)
      - Reading notes from "One Union in the Woods", "Labor Baron - A Portrait of John L. Lewis", and "Sit Down with John L. Lewis", Undated (Box-folder 5/24)
    - MISCELLANEOUS, SERIES XV (Box-folder 5/25, 5/32)
      - Miscellaneous, Undated (Box-folder 5/25)
      - Miscellaneous, Undated (Box-folder 5/32)
    - SUBJECT SERIES, 1933-1952; SERIES XVI (Box-folder 5/26-5/31)
      - Congress of Industrial Organizations (C.I.O.), 1939-1940 (Box-folder 5/26)
      - American Federation of Labor, 1933 (Box-folder 5/27)
      - Seattle Industrial Labor Union Council, Undated (Box-folder 5/28)
      - C.I.O. Political Action Committee, 1952 (Box-folder 5/29)
      - Continuations Committe for an Autonomous and Democratic Washington State Industrial Union Council, 1941 (Box-folder 5/30)
      - Labor's Non-Partisan League, 1939-1940 (Box-folder 5/31)
  - Steelworkers of America, United Local 1208, 1929-1988; Record Subgroup H (Box-folder 6/1-7/1)
    - STEELWORKERS OF AMERICA UNITED LOCAL 1208 MATERIALS, 1929-1988; SERIES I (Box-folder 6/1-7/1)
      - General Correspondence (including Bethelem Steel), 1949-1987 (Box-folder 6/1)
      - Memorandum, 1950-1956 (Box-folder 6/1)
      - Minutes, 1950-1954 (Box-folder 6/1)
      - Reports, 1950-1955 (Box-folder 6/1)